export const ASSESSMENTS = {
  "genetic-engineering": [
    {
      id: 1,
      question:
        "It is the process of manipulating genes in order to have the desired trait.",
      choices: [
        "artificial selection",
        "cloning",
        "genetic engineering",
        "gene splicing",
      ],
      answer: "genetic engineering",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question:
        "It is the process of breeding an organism that are genetically similar to maintain desired traits. It keeps each breed unique from others.",
      choices: [
        "artificial selection",
        "cloning",
        "inbreeding",
        "selective breeding",
      ],
      answer: "inbreeding",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question:
        "It is a technique where the DNA is cut out of one organism and put into another organism. A trait will be transferred from one organism to another.",
      choices: [
        "artificial selection",
        "cloning",
        "gene splicing",
        "gel electrophoresis",
      ],
      answer: "gene splicing",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question:
        "It is a technique of creating an organism that is an exact genetic copy of the other organism.",
      choices: [
        "artificial selection",
        "cloning",
        "gene splicing",
        "gel electrophoresis",
      ],
      answer: "cloning",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question:
        "An applied science of manipulating the genetic material of an organism through artificial selection and biomedical techniques",
      choices: [
        "artificial selection",
        "cloning",
        "genetic engineering",
        "selective breeding",
      ],
      answer: "genetic engineering",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question:
        "It is referred to the joining of almost any nucleotide sequences to create a new gene product or to introduce a new gene sequence.",
      choices: [
        "DNA Recombinant technology",
        "Recombinant DNA technology",
        "both a and b",
        "none of a and b",
      ],
      answer: "Recombinant DNA technology",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question:
        "It is produced chiefly by certain bacteria and has the property of cleaving DNA molecules at or near a specific sequence of bases.",
      choices: [
        "bacteriophage enzymes",
        "plasmid enzymes",
        "restriction enzymes",
        "vector enzymes",
      ],
      answer: "restriction enzymes",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question: "Most common vector used in genetic engineering techniques.",
      choices: [
        "bacteriophage and plasmid",
        "enzymes and plasmid",
        "plasmid and DNA",
        "restriction and DNA",
      ],
      answer: "bacteriophage and plasmid",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question: "All of these are performed to produce recombinant DNA except.",
      choices: [
        "Removal of the genetic sequences of an organism.",
        "Selection of the perfect vector with which the gene has to be integrated.",
        "Insertion of the genetic sequences into other sequences of another organism.",
        "Selection of the perfect enzymes with which the gene has to be integrated",
      ],
      answer:
        "Selection of the perfect enzymes with which the gene has to be integrated",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question: "All of these are tools in recombinant DNA technology except",
      choices: ["enzymes", "host organisms", "restriction enzymes", "vectors"],
      answer: "restriction enzymes",
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      question: "These are ancient practices of genetic engineering except",
      choices: [
        "hybridization",
        "inbreeding",
        "recombinant technology",
        "selective breeding",
      ],
      answer: "recombinant technology",
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      question:
        "Two individuals with unlike characteristics are crossed to produce the best in both organisms.",
      choices: [
        "artificial selection",
        "cloning",
        "genetic engineering",
        "hybridization",
      ],
      answer: "hybridization",
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      question:
        "This is the most commonly used host organism in recombinant DNA technology.",
      choices: ["bacteria", "cells", "plasmid", "vectors"],
      answer: "bacteria",
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      question:
        "I - Since ancient times, the practice of genetic engineering had begun. II - Artificial selection is done to directly manipulate genes focusing on the physical traits among organisms.",
      choices: [
        "Statement I is correct",
        "Statement II is correct",
        "Statement I and II are both correct",
        "Statement I and II are both incorrect",
      ],
      answer: "Statement I is correct",
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      question:
        "I â€“ Enzymes help in recombinant DNA technology by carrying and integrating the desired gene. II - Host organisms are used to propagate the recombinant DNA.",
      choices: [
        "Statement I is correct",
        "Statement II is correct",
        "Statement I and II are both correct",
        "Statement I and II are both incorrect",
      ],
      answer: "Statement II is correct",
    },
  ],
  "organ-systems-of-representative-animals": [
    {
      id: 1,
      question:
        "Which of the following is an example of the endocrine system directly interacting with the nervous system?",
      choices: [
        "The vertebrae protect the spinal cord from injury",
        "Hormones provide feedback that affects neutral processing",
        "Sensory receptors in bones send signals about body position to the brain",
        "The brain sends signals that control the speed at which food moves through the intestines.",
      ],
      answer: "Hormones provide feedback that affects neutral processing",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question:
        "During the final stages of human gestation, receptors for the hormone oxytocin increase on the smooth muscle cells of the uterus. The release of the oxytocin during labor stimulates the smooth muscle tissue in the wall of the uterus. The vigorous contraction of the uterine smooth muscle helps push the baby through the birth canal so that delivery can occur. This process involves the interaction of which organ system?",
      choices: [
        "Endocrine and reproductive only",
        "Endocrine and muscular only",
        "Endocrine, muscular and reproductive",
        "Endocrine, reproductive, and excretory",
      ],
      answer: "Endocrine, muscular and reproductive",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question:
        "Kidneys are part of the excretory system. They purify the impure blood and send it back to the rest of the body. Which system is mainly responsible for the transport of plasma to the kidneys?",
      choices: [
        "Ciculatory systems",
        "Respiratory systems",
        "Nervous systems",
        "Muscular systems",
      ],
      answer: "Ciculatory systems",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question:
        "What two body systems are most useful in getting nutrients from the food that you eat?",
      choices: [
        "Muscular and endocrine systems",
        "Nervous and digestive system",
        "Nervous and circulatory systems",
        "Circulatory and digestive systems",
      ],
      answer: "Circulatory and digestive systems",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question:
        "What two systems work together to provide body cells with a constant supply of oxygen while removing carbon dioxide waste?",
      choices: [
        "Circulatory and respiratory systems",
        "Muscular and circulatory systems",
        "Nervous and circulatory systems",
        "Nervous and immune systems",
      ],
      answer: "Circulatory and respiratory systems",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question:
        "Which of the following describes an interaction that occurs between two body systems of a rabbit that helps the rabbit outrun a pursuing coyote?",
      choices: [
        "The endocrine system releases hormones that prepare the immune system to deal with the possible injuries.",
        "The digestive system increases the rate of digestion, and the excretory deal with the possible injuries.",
        "The respiratory system increases the breathing rate, and the circulatory system increases blood pressure to provide tissues with more oxygen.",
        "The skeletal system releases additional calcium, and the circulatory system retains more sodium in the blood to provide muscles with ions for contraction.",
      ],
      answer:
        "The respiratory system increases the breathing rate, and the circulatory system increases blood pressure to provide tissues with more oxygen.",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question:
        "The human digestive system is approximately 900 cm long. Food is moved through the digestive tract primarily by",
      choices: [
        "Muscular contractions",
        "Bile produces by the pancreas",
        "The enzyme amylase and pepsin",
        "Hydrochloric acid by the stomach",
      ],
      answer: "Muscular contractions",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question:
        "The digestive system is to absorbing nutrients as the circulatory system is to?",
      choices: [
        "Removing nutrients",
        "Attracting nutrients",
        "Distributing nutrients",
        "Fighting infections",
      ],
      answer: "Distributing nutrients",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question:
        "How do circulatory system and immune system work together to respond to an injury?",
      choices: [
        "Increased blood flow carries white blood cells to the site of the injury.",
        "Increased blood flow kills healthy cells which prevents infection at the site of the injury.",
        "Increased blood flow allows for an increase in the exchange of carbon dioxide and oxygen at the site of the injury.",
        "Increased blood flow removes infected cells from the body at the site of the injury.",
      ],
      answer:
        "Increased blood flow carries white blood cells to the site of the injury.",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question:
        "Which body systems must directly interact for a vertebrate organism to exchange gases?",
      choices: [
        "Circulatory and respiratory",
        "Endocrine and respiratory",
        "Immune and endocrine",
        "Skeletal and circulatory",
      ],
      answer: "Circulatory and respiratory",
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      question:
        "A deer hears a predator approaching and begins to run for safety. The deer has primarily engaged what body system to escape?",
      choices: [
        "Muscular, reproductive and circulatory system",
        "Muscular, digestive, and immune system",
        "Nervous, respiratory, and muscular system",
        "Respiratory, endocrine and excretory system",
      ],
      answer: "Nervous, respiratory, and muscular system",
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      question:
        "Which two systems alert the young bird from danger and help produce the vomit it uses as a defense?",
      choices: [
        "Excretory and immune",
        "Muscular and digestive",
        "Nervous and digestive",
        "Urinary and muscular",
      ],
      answer: "Nervous and digestive",
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      question:
        "Which of the following is an example of the endocrine system directly interacting with the nervous system?",
      choices: [
        "The vertebrae protect the spinal cord from injury",
        "Hormones provide feedback that affects neuron processing",
        "Sensory receptors in bones send signals about body position to the brain",
        "The brain sends signal that control the speed at which food moves through the intestines",
      ],
      answer: "Hormones provide feedback that affects neuron processing",
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      question:
        "Which body systems work together to protect the body from pathogens?",
      choices: [
        "Circulatory and immune",
        "Digestive and excretory",
        "Endocrine and reproductive",
        "Muscular and vascular",
      ],
      answer: "Circulatory and immune",
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      question: "How does the digestive system work with all other systems?",
      choices: [
        "The digestive system allows the body to move",
        "The digestive system puts oxygen into the body",
        "The digestive system gives the body energy and nutrients",
        "The digestive system transport blood to all the other systems",
      ],
      answer: "The digestive system gives the body energy and nutrients",
    },
  ],
  "process-of-evolution": [
    {
      id: 1,
      question: "Refers to a change over time",
      choices: ["evolution", "gradualism", "migration", "mutation"],
      answer: "evolution",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question:
        "Each living species has descended, with changes, from other species over time and as a result species today look different from their ancestors",
      choices: [
        "Theory of Descent with Modification",
        "Theory of Modification",
        "Theory of Natural Selection",
        "Theory of Survival",
      ],
      answer: "Theory of Descent with Modification",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question:
        "Explains the difference in survival of individuals and how they reproduce in a particular environment",
      choices: ["evolution", "gene flow", "gradualism", "natural selection"],
      answer: "natural selection",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question:
        "Takes place when population decreases due to various environmental factors such as fires, earthquakes and floods",
      choices: [
        "bottleneck effect",
        "founder effect",
        "genetic flow",
        "natural selection",
      ],
      answer: "bottleneck effect",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question:
        "The process of the movement of genes from one population to another",
      choices: ["evolution", "gene flow", "gradualism", "natural selection"],
      answer: "gene flow",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question: "Which of the following is considered as mechanisms of change?",
      choices: [
        "genetic drift",
        "migration",
        "natural selection",
        "a, b and c",
      ],
      answer: "a, b and c",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question: "Changes in the DNA",
      choices: [
        "gene flow",
        "genetic shuffling",
        "genetic variation",
        "mutation",
      ],
      answer: "mutation",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question: "This is also called migration",
      choices: [
        "gene flow",
        "genetic shuffling",
        "genetic variation",
        "mutation",
      ],
      answer: "gene flow",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question:
        "Differences among individuals of a species are referred to as ______",
      choices: [
        "adaption",
        "fitness",
        "natural selection",
        "natural variation",
      ],
      answer: "natural variation",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question: "Father of Evolution",
      choices: [
        "Alfred Russel Wallace",
        "Carolus Linnaeus",
        "Charles Darwin",
        "Jean Baptiste de Lamarck",
      ],
      answer: "Charles Darwin",
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      question: "Proposed the Theory of Use and Disuse",
      choices: [
        "Alfred Russel Wallace",
        "Carolus Linnaeus",
        "Charles Darwin",
        "Jean Baptiste de Lamarck",
      ],
      answer: "Jean Baptiste de Lamarck",
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      question:
        "Believed that populations grow geometrically while resources slowly increase leading to competition.",
      choices: [
        "Alfred Russel Wallace",
        "Carolus Linnaeus",
        "Jean Baptiste de Lamarck",
        "Thomas Malthus",
      ],
      answer: "Thomas Malthus",
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      question: "Father of Taxonomy",
      choices: [
        "Alfred Russel Wallace",
        "Carolus Linnaeus",
        "Jean Baptiste de Lamarck",
        "Thomas Malthus",
      ],
      answer: "Carolus Linnaeus",
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      question:
        "According to this Theory of Evolution, organisms change during their lifetime",
      choices: [
        "Carolus Linnaeus",
        "Charles Darwin",
        "Jean Baptiste de Lamarck",
        "Thomas Malthus",
      ],
      answer: "Jean Baptiste de Lamarck",
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      question: "His theory involves natural selection",
      choices: [
        "Carolus Linnaeus",
        "Charles Darwin",
        "Jean Baptiste de Lamarck",
        "Thomas Malthus",
      ],
      answer: "Charles Darwin",
    },
  ],
  "interaction-and-interdependence": [
    {
      id: 1,
      question:
        "What biotic relationship occurs in organism where one species is benefited while the other is harmed?",
      choices: ["commensalism", "mutualism", "parasitism", "predation"],
      answer: "parasitism",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question:
        "Which of the following is an example of environmental resistance?",
      choices: [
        "various predators may compete for a similar prey",
        "suitable habitat restrains the growth of producers",
        "change in seasons can influence conduct of living beings",
        "desert biological systems have restricted life forms because of outrageous parched conditions",
      ],
      answer: "various predators may compete for a similar prey",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question: "What are the two important relationships in an ecosystem?",
      choices: [
        "symbiosis and predation",
        "mutualism and parasitism",
        "interaction and interdependence",
        "biotic potential and environmental resistance",
      ],
      answer: "interaction and interdependence",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question:
        "Which of the following condition does NOT show abiotic factors in an ecosystem?",
      choices: [
        "cactus growing in hot, dry regions",
        "earthworm burrowing for habitation",
        "polar bears living in a very cold environment",
        "A young woman gave birth to a healthy baby boy",
      ],
      answer: "polar bears living in a very cold environment",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question:
        "The carrying capacity is the maximum number of organisms that an ecosystem can support. What factors influence the carrying capacity?",
      factors:
        "I. competition | II. limiting factor | III. biotic potential | IV. environmental resistance",
      choices: ["I and II", "I and III", "III and IV", "I, II, and IV"],
      answer: "III and IV",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question: "What factors control the increase in population growth?",
      factors:
        "I. water | II. disease | III. sunlight | IV. predation | V. competitors | VI. temperature | VII. adequate food | VIII. unsuitable habitat",
      choices: [
        "II, IV, V, VII",
        "I, III, V, VIII",
        "I, III, IV, V",
        "II, IV, V, VIII",
      ],
      answer: "II, IV, V, VIII",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question:
        "The biotic and abiotic factors that prevent the growth of a population like food, water and space is called?",
      choices: [
        "limiting factor",
        "biotic potential",
        "carrying capacity",
        "environmental resistance",
      ],
      answer: "limiting factor",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question:
        "Which refers to the symbiotic relationship in which both organisms are benefited?",
      choices: ["commensalism", "mutualism", "parasitism", "predation"],
      answer: "mutualism",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question:
        "Which of the following essential factors determines biotic potential",
      choices: [
        "diseases",
        "lack of food",
        "number of offspring",
        "lack of suitable habitat",
      ],
      answer: "number of offspring",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question:
        "What do you call the area in which living things interact with one another and with their environment?",
      choices: ["commmunity", "ecosystem", "habitat", "population"],
      answer: "ecosystem",
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      question:
        "What is the connection betweeen biotic potential and environmental resistance?",
      choices: [
        "Biotic potential increases the population whereas environmental resistance confines its growth.",
        "Biotic potential increases the population while environmental resistance decreases its growth.",
        "Biotic potential and environmental resistance are the two factors that increase the population growth.",
        "Biotic potential and environmental resistance are the two factors that limit the population explosion.",
      ],
      answer:
        "Biotic potential increases the population while environmental resistance decreases its growth.",
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      question:
        "Which of the accompanying reasons does explain why various life forms have diverse biotic potentials?",
      choices: [
        "Offspring have distinctive survival rates.",
        "Life forms have diverse multiplication rates.",
        "Different life forms will have diverse reproductive life expectancies.",
        "Organisms that abide in a similar situtation will have similar potentials.",
      ],
      answer:
        "Organisms that abide in a similar situtation will have similar potentials.",
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      question:
        "What is the symbiotic relationship in an ecosystem when one organism benefits and the other is unaffected?",
      choices: ["Commensalism", "Mutualism", "Parasitism", "Predation"],
      answer: "Commensalism",
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      question:
        "What is the type of interaction when the two species use the same limited resources and struggle with one another to survive?",
      choices: ["Competition", "Mutualism", "Predation", "Symbiosis"],
      answer: "Competition",
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      question: "What is the role of predator in the ecosystem?",
      choices: [
        "Remove vulnerable prey",
        "Increase the number of prey",
        "Have no effect in the ecosystem",
        "Decrease the number of predator",
      ],
      answer: "Remove vulnerable prey",
    },
  ],
  "marine-and-coastal-processes": [
    {
      id: 1,
      question: "Which of the following is NOT a coastal process?",
      choices: ["landslides", "storm surge", "tides", "waves"],
      answer: "landslides",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question:
        "Which of the following is caused by the gravitational pull of the moon and Earth?",
      choices: ["sea level rise", "storm surge", "tides", "tsunami"],
      answer: "sea level rise",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question:
        "Which of the following is attributed to the rising of sea level in the polar region?",
      choices: ["continent", "crust", "glacier", "snow"],
      answer: "glacier",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question:
        "What refers to the rising of seawater due to pressure and wind associated with a storm?",
      choices: ["crustal movement", "storm surge", "tides", "waves"],
      answer: "storm surge",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question:
        "Which of the following statements is NOT TRUE about coastal processes?",
      choices: [
        "Beach is prone to erosion.",
        "Erosion only occurs in the upland areas.",
        "Wind is a contributory factor to storm surge.",
        "Ocean waves cause water to move in the seashore.",
      ],
      answer: "Wind is a contributory factor to storm surge.",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question: "Which of the following is NOT a coastal hazard?",
      choices: [
        "coastal erosion",
        "landslide",
        "saltwater intrusion",
        "submersion",
      ],
      answer: "landslides",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question:
        "What is described as an induced flow of seawater into freshwater aquifers primarily caused by groundwater development near the coast?",
      choices: [
        "coastal erosion",
        "saltwater intrusion",
        "storm surge",
        "submersion",
      ],
      answer: "saltwater intrusion",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question: "Which of the following is NOT an agent of coastal erosion?",
      choices: ["land pollution", "ocean waves", "storms", "tides"],
      answer: "land pollution",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question:
        "What do you call the movement of sediments from the visible portion of a beach to the nearshore region of the coast?",
      choices: [
        "coastal erosion",
        "saltwater intrusion",
        "storm surge",
        "submersion",
      ],
      answer: "submersion",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question:
        "Which of the following coastal processes may cause hazards in the marine environment?",
      choices: ["crustal movement", "tides", "waves", "all of the above"],
      answer: "all of the above",
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      question:
        "What do you call the scientific study of the chemical, biological and physical properties of ocean water?",
      choices: ["Biology", "Chemistry", "Oceanography", "Physics"],
      answer: "Oceanography",
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      question: "Where can we usually find aquifers?",
      choices: [
        "underground",
        "in the ocean waves",
        "on the top of the mountain",
        "top surface of the rivers",
      ],
      answer: "underground",
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      question: "What two ions compose mainly the seawater?",
      choices: [
        "hydrogen and oxygen",
        "hydrogen and potassium",
        "nitrogen and phosphorus",
        "sodium and chlorine",
      ],
      answer: "nitrogen and phosphorus",
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      question: "Which system is broader?",
      choices: [
        "coastal system",
        "marine system",
        "both A and B",
        "neither A nor B",
      ],
      answer: "coastal system",
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      question:
        "As a student, what ways can you do to help adapt and mitigate coastal hazards?",
      choices: [
        "Educate yourself.",
        "Promote the programs of the community.",
        "Participate in local disaster preparedness program.",
        "All of the above",
      ],
      answer: "All of the above",
    },
  ],
};
